fabric fit and timeless style and that hasn't changed since the day we opened
our doors we've always looked at what's new what's next
incorporating fabric and timeless style into our innovation a number of years
ago I saw 3d I literally called Andrew and I said Andrew we have to have this
this would save a lot of time and a lot of effort done this now for two
different retailers that will have ideas we'll do it all in 3d and we'll see what
it looks like before we even make sample one and we'll show it to the retailers
that way so we're actually saving a lot of time and a lot of money and
eventually I think it's going to enhance our creativity because we'll be able to
do things even faster
when we first started looking at 3d software what Chloe offered us was that
their focus is on the front end the creative process and that really matched
you know what our business is looking for in a 3d tool you're able to look at
something that's much more meaningful than a sketch or a line sheet you're
able to see what the actual product looks like without having to manufacture
an actual sample certain categories that may have been challenging with other
software
we were able to create our full line using clo much more user-friendly for
designers and merchandisers and that business partnership is very key in
having that buy-in and really engage our designers and merchandisers in use of
the tool
our vision is not to look at this as a 3d project but rather this is just now
the way we work we want them to use this instead of the traditional methods of
hand sketching
and using tools like Adobe Illustrator.
We're going to use 3D end-to-end
all the way through manufacturing of the garment,
having this 3D model living
with the actual specifications and samples.
It just becomes part of the overall process.
The previous 3D that we were using,
you couldn't design on it.
Chlo has taken it even further
than I had originally imagined.
And designing things and putting the fabrics in them
so that the fabrics can drape properly
and determining, oh, you know, I really want that fabric,
or you know what, that fabric's not really right.
And not even wanting a sample yardage.
I mean, there's so many opportunities for the future.
It's really exciting.